Guide to the James Major Baley Papers, 1938-1954 RL.00073
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
James Major Baley papers
1938-1954
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Baley, James Major, 1912-
RL.00073
1 Linear Feet
217 Items
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research.
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
All or portions of this collection may be housed off-site in Duke University's Library Service Center. The library may require up to 48 hours to retrieve these materials for research use.
Please contact Research Services staff before visiting the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library to use this collection.
Provenance
The David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library received the collection as a gift from James Major Baley (1912-) of Marshall, N.C. on October 22, 1956.
Biographical Note
James Major Baley (1912-) was a judge on the Court of Appeals in the 1970s.
Collection Overview
This collection consists of official letters, speeches, data concerning party organization, newspaper clippings, printed matter (both from the state Republican Party and the national executive committee), a list of contributors to the state party in 1952, official press releases, and financial records.
Baley, James Major, 1912-
- James Major Baley Papers, 1938-1954, 5 boxes
  - Financial Papers, 1940's (Box 1)
  - Financial Papers, 1930's (Box 1)
  - Financial Papers, 1950's (Box 1)
  - Bank Statements and Checks, 1951-1952 (Box 1)
  - Bank Statements and Checks, 1952-1953 (Box 1)
  - Various Financial Records, various dates and undated (Box 1)
  - Various Financial Records, various dates and undated (Box 1)
  - Check Book, 1950-1953 (Box 2)
  - Check Book, 1950-1952 (Box 2)
  - Speeches, various dates and undated (Box 2)
  - Speeches and Notes, various dates and undated (Box 2)
  - News Releases, 1940's-1950's and undated (Box 2)
  - Clippings, 1948 (Box 2)
  - Clippings, 1940-1947 (Box 2)
  - Clippings, 1948 (Box 2)
  - Clippings, 1950-1954 (Box 2)
  - Clippings, undated (Box 2)
  - Printed Material, 1934-1947 (Box 3)
  - Printed Material, 1948 (Box 3)
  - Printed Material, 1950-1952 (Box 3)
  - Printed Material, undated (Box 3)
  - Correspondence, 1938-1939 (Box 3)
  - Correspondence, 1940 (Box 3)
  - Correspondence, 1941-1945 (Box 3)
  - Correspondence, 1946 (Box 3)
  - Correspondence, 1947-1949 (Box 3)
  - Correspondence, 1950-1952 (Box 3)
  - Correspondence, undated (Box 3)
  - Party Papers, 1938-1946 (Box 4)
  - Party Papers, undated (Box 4)
  - Party Papers, 1948-1953 (Box 4)
  - Party Papers, undated (Box 4)
  - Contributions, various dates and undated (Box 5)